A Finding Aid to the Esther McCoy Papers, circa 1876-1990, bulk 1938-1989, in the Archives of American Art AAA.mccoesth
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1896-1989; Series 2; (Boxes 1-6, 4.9 linear feet)
  - Family Correspondence, 1896-1988; 2.1
    - McCoy, James L., Personal and Business Correspondence, 1920-1945 (Box 2, Folder 8-10)
    - McCoy, John, to Esther McCoy, circa 1940s-1950, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - McCoy, Julia Stephens, to Frank McCoy, 1928-1937 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - McCoy, William, to Esther McCoy, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Various Family Members, 1896-1916, 1933-circa 1970s (Box 2, Folder 14-16)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1908-1989; 2.2
    This subseries contains personal correspondence between McCoy and her friends, lovers, and colleagues. The letters concern McCoy's personal and love relationships, her views on politics, culture, and the literary world, and her struggles as a writer.
    Correspondence between McCoy and lovers, including Geoffrey Eaton, John Mitchell, John Vick, Albert Robert (also known as "Timmie"), and her husband, Berkeley Tobey, is especially well represented. Much of the extensive correspondence between McCoy and Albert Robert is undated. A few letters between McCoy and her lovers include photographs.
    There is also significant correspondence with fellow writers, including Theodore Dreiser, Ray Bradbury, Millen Brand, John Collier, John Cowper Powys, and historian Lewis Mumford. Correspondence with Ray Bradbury includes discussions of theater, art and architecture. Letters from Helen Dreiser include Dreiser's opinions on manuscripts written by McCoy. Theodore Dreiser's letters provide insight into the research assignments McCoy carried out for Dreiser and his opinions of her writing. The letters include the typescript of a poem, possibly written by Dreiser. William A. Swanberg, who wrote a book on Dreiser, sought McCoy's opinions and impressions of the author, and their correspondence includes many observations and theories concerning Dreiser's personal life. Also of note is extensive correspondence between McCoy and her close friend Katheryn (Kay) Metz.
    Folders are arranged alphabetically; within folders, material is chronological.
    - Babb, Dorothy, 1951, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Bradbury, Ray, 1958-1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Brand, Millen and Helen, 1948-1951, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Collier, John and Harriet, circa 1953-1978 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
    - Darrow, Clarence, to Geoffrey Eaton, February 23, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Dreiser, Helen, circa 1939-1955 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Dreiser, Theodore, circa 1924-1943 (Box 2, Folder 24-28)
    - Dreiser, Theodore, Undated Letters, circa 1926-1938 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Dreiser, Vera, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Durden, Jim, 1951-1985 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Eaton, Geoffrey, 1926-1929 (Box 2, Folder 32-37)
    - Eaton, Geoffrey, Undated Letters, circa 1926-1929 (Box 2, Folder 38-39)
    - Evans, Jean, 1941-1979 (Box 2, Folder 40-41)
    - Grainger, Boyne (Bonnie), 1931-1950s (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Grotz, Dorothy, Paul and Stefan, circa 1958-1989 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Hanson, Ruth, circa 1967-1989 (Box 2, Folder 44-45)
    - Hunt, Nolya, circa 1923-1951; (includes photographs, possibly of Hunt, and illustrated letters) (Box 2, Folder 46-48)
    - Kahn, Gordon, circa 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 49-51)
    - Kuifer, John, circa 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Lee, Cora Vernon, Regarding Lee's Estate, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Metz, Kathryn (Kay), 1951, 1961-1989; (includes an original print by Metz) (Box 3, Folder 1-8)
    - Mitchell, John, 1928-1933 (Box 3, Folder 9-11)
    - Mitchell, John, Undated Letters, circa 1928-1933 (Box 3, Folder 12-14)
    - Mitchell, John, Personal and Business Correspondence, 1929-1932 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Mumford, Lewis, 1953-1963, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Powys, John Cowper, 1934, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Read, Allan, 1928, 1935-1938, circa 1952 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Robert, Albert, circa 1925, 1932-1934 (Box 3, Folder 19-21)
    - Robert, Albert, circa 1935 (Box 3, Folder 22-26)
    - Robert, Albert, 1936-1942 (Box 3, Folder 27-32)
    - Robert, Albert, Undated Letters, circa 1932-1942 (Box 3, Folder 33-48)
    - Robert, Albert, Undated Letters, circa 1932-1942 (Box 4, Folder 1-6)
    - Robert, Albert, Photographs found with Letters to Esther McCoy, circa 1930s (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Robert, Albert, Personal and Business Correspondence, 1930-1940 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Spence, Andy and Sique, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Swanberg, William A., 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Tobey, Berkeley, circa 1944-1959 (Box 4, Folder 11-14)
    - Tobey, Berkeley, Personal and Business Correspondence, 1908-1909 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Tobey, Berkeley, Personal and Business Correspondence, 1922-1940 (Box 4, Folder 16-19)
    - Tobey, Berkeley, Personal and Business Correspondence, 1941-1952 (Box 4, Folder 20-23)
    - University of Pennsylvania (regarding her donation of Dreiser's letters), 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Van der Velde, Edward, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Vick, John, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Vick, John, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 27-31)
    - Vick, John, 1925-1927; (includes photographs of Vick) (Box 4, Folder 32-35)
    - Vick, John, Undated Letters, circa 1923-1927 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Weigel, Henrietta, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - General Correspondence, 1922-1989; 2.3
    This subseries primarily contains letters concerning McCoy's career in architectural history and criticism. Her career in fiction writing is covered to a lesser degree. Among the correspondents are researchers, writers, professors, architects, art professionals, publishers, and professional associations. Topics covered include research and writing projects, Los Angeles area preservation and restoration projects, and grant projects.
    Major correspondents in this series include the American Institute of Architects, the Graham Foundation, City of Los Angeles Cultural Heritage Board, Domus Magazine, Los Angeles Times, editor Monica Pidgeon, architectural critics Reyner Banham, David Gebhard, William Jordy, Robin Middleton, Allan Temko, and Nathan Shapira, and architects J. R. Davidson, Craig Ellwood, Joseph Giovannini, Hans Hollein, A. Quincy Jones, and Bruno Zevi. Also found is extensive correspondence with the University of California, Berkeley, Santa Barbara, and Santa Cruz. Correspondence for 1959 contains a letter from Albert Camus requesting McCoy's assistance with helping Spanish refugees, and correspondence for 1989 contains photographs of Esther McCoy and others at the Athenaeum at Caltech for the third annual gala of the Historical Society of Southern California.
    See index for a select list of correspondents.
    Material is arranged chronologically. The bulk of McCoy's correspondence with architects is arranged in Series 6: Architect Files. Additional correspondence pertaining to specific projects can be found in Series 4: Architectural Writings and in Series 5: Project Files. Correspondence in this series complements the files found in these other series and they should be consulted together for a better understanding of McCoy's career.
    Indexes
    Index of Correspondents from Series 2.3: General Correspondence
    Abbot, Mary Squire (McIntosh and Otis, Inc.), 1949, 1950, 1953, 1957
    Adahura, Yuki, 1942
    Adams, Christopher, 1962
    Albinson, Don, 1989
    Alexander, Christopher, 1965
    Allen, Albert, 1968
    Amantea, Kirjah, 1982
    Ambre, Reuth, 1986
    American Academy in Rome, 1970
    American Federation of Arts, 1966
    American Film Institute, 1975
    American Institute of Architects, 1959, 1967, 1968, 1969, 1972, 1973, 1977, 1978, 1979, 1980, 1981, 1982, 1983, 1984, 1985, 1987, 1988, 1989
    American Institute of Interior Designers, 1974
    Anderson, Sherwood, undated
    Andrews, Wayne, 1983
    Architecture, 1985
    Architecture in Australia, 1974
    Architectural Forum, 1965, 1966, 1968
    Architectural History Foundation, Inc., 1982, 1983, 1984
    Architectural Publishing Co., 1967
    Architectural Record, 1959
    Archive of Women in Architecture, 1975
    Archives of American Art, 1984, 1985, 1986, 1987, 1989
    Arizona Quarterly, 1949
    Arizona State University, 1969
    Arts in Society, 1964
    Ashton, Raymond J., 1948
    Ashton, Ruth (KNX Radio), 1964
    Atkinson, Janet Irene, 1980, 1985
    Author and Journalist, 1951
    Bailey, Van Evera, 1953
    Baldauf, Lisa, 1989
    Balint, Dr. D. P., 1963
    Banham, Reyner (Peter) and Mary, 1964, 1966, 1967, 1969, 1970, 1971, 1973, 1979, 1982, 1983, 1988, 1989, undated
    Barnette-Stratford, Mrs. Lou, 1968
    Barsocchini, Michael, 1970
    Beach, John, 1984
    Beebe, Tina, 1989
    Behrman, S. N., 1960
    Belluschi, Pietro, 1949
    Beltram Carla, 1966
    Bendixson, T. M. P., 1961
    Bennett, Janey, 1986
    Berkeley, Ellen Perry, 1975, 1987, 1988, undated
    Bicknell, Catherine, 1985
    Birkmeyer, Karl, 1968
    Blanton, John, 1988
    Blau, Milton, 1947
    Boaz, Joseph N., 1949
    Bowlby, Bob, 1983, 1989
    Boyer, John, 1982
    Brant, Sandra, 1975
    Brooks, Allen, 1975
    "The Bradbury Girls," 1972
    Brunati, Mario, 1963, 1965, 1966
    California Coastal Commission, 1977, 1978
    California Council of Architects, 1957
    California Department of Parks and Recreation, 1973
    California Historical Society, 1979
    California Magazine, 1985, 1986
    California Polytechnic State University, 1978, 1984
    California State Office for Historic Preservation, 1978
    Camus, Albert, 1959
    Carrott, Richard, 1973
    Carson, Sam, 1969
    Casabella (Gian Antonio Bernasconi), 1965
    Charles Scribner's Sons, 1930
    Chang, Ching Yu, 1977, undated
    Chase, John, undated
    Chermayeff, Serge, undated
    Choate, Forrest, 1986
    Christian Science Monitor, 1987
    City Attorney, Santa Monica, California, 1968
    City of Beverly Hills, 1982, 1983, 1984
    City of Los Angeles, Cultural Heritage Board, 1963, 1966, 1967, 1969, 1973, 1974, 1982, 1983, 1987, 1988
    Clark, Alson, 1984, undated
    Cochran, Victor E., 1953
    Cohen, Elaine Lustig, 1985
    Cohen, Stuart, 1979
    Colgan, Susan, 1979
    Collier's, 1953
    Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc., 1947, 1948
    Columbia University, 1972, 1973
    Communication Dynamics, 1963
    Compagnia Nazionale Artigiana, 1956, 1960
    Contini, Edgardo, 1963
    Correa, Frederico, 1975
    Craft and Folk Art Museum, 1983
    Cragar, Robert, 1949, 1950
    Craig, Mary, 1945
    Crosbie, Michael, 1985, 1987, 1988, 1989
    Cross, Paula, 1981
    Culot, Maurice, 1972, 1973
    Curtis, William, 1982, 1985, 1987, 1989
    Dailey, Gardner A., 1948
    Dale, John R., 1989
    Davidson, Barnaby, 1984
    Davidson, Carlos, 1984
    Davidson, Erica, 1983, undated
    Davidson, J. R. and Greta, 1973, 1974, 1976, 1977, 1978, undated
    Davidson, Tom, 1981, undated
    Day, Peter, 1985
    De Bretteville, Peter and Sheila (The Woman's Building), 1975, 1976, 1977, 1978
    De Long, James, 1947
    Dearborn-Massar, 1961
    Delano, Leonard H., 1949
    Design Quarterly, 1975, 1987
    Dictionary of American Biography, 1975
    Dictionary of Art, 1986
    Diefenbach, John, 1973
    Dimster, Frank, 1966
    Dixon, John Morris, 1979
    Domus (Lisa Licitra Ponti), 1970, 1971, 1972, 1973, 1974, 1975, 1981, 1982
    Donohoe, Victoria, 1965, undated
    Dorman, Richard, 1970
    Dougherty, Carole, 1989, undated
    Downing, Holly, 1974
    Dudley, George, 1984, 1988, undated
    Dukeminier, Jesse, Jr., 1967
    Dyson, Arthur, 1985, 1987
    Easton, Bob, 1977
    Eckbo, Gerrett, 1977, 1982
    Eder, Richard, 1987, 1988
    Edilizia Moderna, 1965
    Eisner, Richard K., undated
    Elliott, James, 1986
    Ellwood, Craig, 1967, 1968, 1971, 1984, 1988
    Elwyn, Adolph, 1946
    Emanuel, Muriel, 1979
    Emmons, Donn, 1975
    E. P. Dutton and Co., 1975
    Favro, Diane, 1987
    Fetherson, Kate, 1979, 1980, 1981, 1988
    Feiss, Carl, 1948, 1949
    Field, Ellen, 1964
    Filler, Martin, 1986
    Fisher, Shirley, 1978
    Flack, Peter, 1975
    Fonda-Bonardi, Mario, 1989
    Ford, Edward R., 1986
    Foreign Service of the United States of America, 1959, 1962
    Forsyth, Robert J., 1961, 1962
    Fortune, 1936
    Francis, Marcia, 1979
    Franks, Milton, 1962
    Franzen, Ulrich, 1968, 1969
    Frey, Albert, 1988
    Friends of Cast Iron Architecture, 1972, 1974, 1977, undated
    Friends of Kebyar, 1984
    Fulton, Weldon, undated
    Gebhard, David, 1963, 1964, 1965, 1966, 1967, 1968, 1969, 1970, 1972, 1973, 1974, 1975, 1977, 1979, 1980, 1981, 1982, 1983, 1984, 1985, 1986, 1987, 1988, undated
    Geddes, Robert L., 1977
    General Services Administration, 1973
    Giella, Alfonso and Bobbi, 1967, 1974, 1982
    Gill, Dorothy, 1985
    Giovannini, Joseph (Gio), 1979, 1981, 1986, 1988, 1989, undated
    Goldberger, Paul, 1972, 1973, 1975
    Goldman, Shifra M., 1979, undated
    Goldstein, Barbara, 1981, 1982, 1985, 1989, undated
    Gordon, Don, 1980, undated
    Gould, Jean, 1965
    Graham Foundation for Studies in the Fine Arts (Carter Manny), 1964, 1965, 1966, 1968, 1969, 1970, 1971, 1974, 1975, 1978, 1979, 1981, 1983, 1984, 1985, 1986, 1987, undated
    Granger, Kathleen, 1981
    Gray, Paul, 1977
    Greenbaum, Katherine, 1980
    Greene, Herb, 1971, 1972, 1976, undated
    Greenhill, Nigel, 1973
    Gregory, Dan, 1982, 1984, 1986, 1987
    Guss, Jack, 1961
    Hall, Milly, 1970, 1976, 1977
    Hanks, David, 1986
    Harnish, John, 1960
    Harper and Row, 1979
    Harper's Bazaar, 1951, 1952, 1961
    Harris, Robert, 1981, 1982
    Harvard Architecture Review, 1977, 1979
    Harvey, Harold E., 1972, 1973
    Haupt, Peter, 1967
    Hayden, Dolores, 1984, undated
    Helene Wurlitzer Foundation of New Mexico, 1967, 1969
    Hernandez, Diana, 1976, undated
    Herron, Ron, 1969
    Hess, Alan, 1985
    Hillyer, Elinor, 1949
    Hinerfeld, Susan and Robert, 1984
    Hines, Tom, 1971, 1975
    Historical Society of Southern California, 1988, 1989
    Hitchcock, H. R., 1956
    Hite, Garron S., 1972
    Hoag, Paul Sterling, 1981
    Hollein, Hans, 1960, 1963, 1964, 1965, 1966, 1972, 1976, 1984, undated
    Hollywood Revitalization Committee, 1979
    Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 1977
    Houvener, Robert, 1969
    Howe, John H., 1980
    Howe, Sanora Babb, 1980, 1982, 1989
    Humanities West, 1984, 1985
    Huxley, Aldus, 1960
    Ingalls, David K., 1987
    Interiors, 1984, 1985
    Istituto Nazionale per il Commercio Estero, 1970
    Jansen, Virginia, 1978
    Japan Architect, 1968
    Jarrico, Paul, 1971
    Johnson, Mark R., 1981
    Jokl, Magda, 1978
    Jonas, Susan, 1963
    Jones, A. Quincy and Elaine, 1968, 1969, 1970, 1971, 1974, 1975, 1979, 1981, 1984, 1986, 1987, 1988, undated
    Jordy, William H., 1959, 1961, 1967, 1972, 1973, 1974, 1977, 1978, 1979, 1984
    Jourdan, Erven, 1951
    Jurney, David, 1957
    Kahn, Louis, 1960
    Kamerling, Bruce, 1980, 1985
    Kappe, Raymond and Shelly, 1970, 1973
    Kazin, Alfred, 1961, 1984
    KCRW 89.9 FM, 1989
    Kennedy, Jacqueline (letter to and reply from secretary), 1964
    Kershner, Irvin, 1960
    Khoury, E. M., 1960, 1963
    Killingsworth, Edward, 1989
    King, Jean, 1975, 1977, 1987, undated
    King, Robert I., 1963
    Kirsch, Jonathan, 1977
    Koeper, Fred, 1980
    Kotas, Jerry, 1971, 1973, undated
    Kripacz, Francisco, 1985
    Kultermann, Udo, 1967
    Lagorio, Elena, 1975
    La Jolla Museum of Contemporary Art, 1977, 1986
    Lamb, Paul, 1982
    Landau, Sarah B., 1971
    Langer, Elinor, 1975, 1983
    Lawson, John Howard (Jack), 1947
    Lebovich, William, 1979
    Lee, Joyce, 1975
    Leedy, Walter, 1970, 1971, 1972, 1973, 1976, undated
    Legorreta, Ricardo, 1971
    Lehman, John, 1948
    Le Veque, Ann, 1980
    Library of Congress, 1983
    Lindauer, Theodore, 1983
    Lingeman, Richard, 1986, 1987
    Longstreth, Richard, 1982
    Lorman, William, 1954
    Los Angeles Conservancy, 1984, 1986
    Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 1966, 1967, 1982
    Los Angeles Times, 1957, 1959, 1960, 1966, 1968, 1969, 1971, 1976, 1977, 1978, 1980, 1981, 1983, 1985
    Lovell, Gary, 1968, 1978
    Lovell, Leah, 1960
    Lovell, Philip, 1968, 1972
    Lowenkopf, Anne, 1975
    Lumsden, Anthony, 1969, 1974
    Luna, Fernando, 1971, 1974
    Lyman, Frederic, 1974, 1989
    Lyndon, Maynard, 1983, 1984, undated
    MacDowell Colony Fellows, 1988
    Mangiarotti, Angelo, 1970
    Manson, Grant, 1974
    Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1984
    Maston, Carl, 1969, 1970, 1972
    May, Cliff, 1983, 1985
    McCoy, John, 1954, 1976, 1977, 1979, 1981, 1986, 1987, 1988
    McCoy, Tori, 1974
    McCulloch, Peter, 1962
    McWilliams, Carey, 1980
    Mendelsohn, Mrs. Eric, 1974, 1975
    Meyer, Kurt, 1969
    Middleton, Robin, 1971, 1972, 1973, 1974, 1975, 1976, 1977, 1978, 1979, 1980, 1981, 1982, 1983, 1984, 1986, 1987, 1988
    Mies Van Der Rohe Centennial Project, 1984
    Miller, R. Craig, 1973
    Miller, Donald M., 1986
    Minister, Chancery of Pakistan, 1965
    Moholy-Nagy, Sibyl, 1966, 1969
    Mouton, Pierre, 1986, 1988, 1989
    Muller, Louis, 1988
    Murphy, William (Bill), 1969, 1970, 1982, 1983, 1984, 1985, 1986, 1987, 1988, 1989, undated
    Museum of Contemporary Art, Los Angeles, 1984, 1985, 1986, 1987, 1989
    Museum of Fine Arts, Houston, 1976
    Museum of Modern Art, 1961, 1964, 1976
    Mutlow, John, 1982
    Nakamura, Toshio, 1981, 1982, 1984, 1985
    National Building Museum, 1981
    National Committee for the Defense of Political Prisoners, 1933
    National Endowment for the Arts, 1971, 1975, 1980, 1981, 1982
    National Trust for Historic Preservation, 1970, 1971, 1972, 1973, 1977
    Nelson, June Kompass, 1985
    Nelson, Sara, 1974
    New West, 1976
    New Yorker, 1953, 1962, 1968, 1974, 1975, 1876, undated
    Nichols, Henry L., 1982, 1987
    Nishimoto, Kenneth, 1959, 1968
    Nixon, Peg and Chuck, 1976, 1989, undated
    North Carolina State University, 1983
    Novotny, Norbert, 1973
    Nunis, Doyce, Jr., 1989
    Oakley, Susan H., 1974
    O'Gorman, Brit and Peter, 1983
    O'Gorman, James F., 1973, 1984
    Ohannesian, Paul B., 1978, 1979
    On Site, 1975
    Owen, Tom, 1963, undated
    Pacific Design Center, 1985
    Palazzo Dell'Edilizia, 1963, 1964
    Pan American World Airways System, 1955, 1956
    Pardee, Clark, 1989
    Park, Donald, 1986
    Park, Helen, 1979
    Paul, Stella, 1988
    Peregrine Press, 1971, 1977, 1986, 1989
    Perspecta (Jeff Limerick), 1961, 1975, 1976, undated
    Pflueger, Donald, 1989
    Pidgeon, Monica, 1973, 1974, 1980, 1982, 1986
    Plantin Press, Ltd., 1984
    Praeger Publishers, Inc., 1972
    Price, Joe D., 1969
    Price, Martin, 1964
    Prinsloo, Ivor, 1988
    Producer-Writers Guild of America Pension Plan, 1960
    Pyne Press, 1974
    Rand, Marvin, 1989
    Read, Gardner, 1968
    Reinhold Book Division, 1968
    Reinhold Publishing Division, 1960, 1970
    Rhode Island Historical Society, 1977
    Rhode Island School of Design, 1977
    Ricasoli, Bettino, 1960
    Ricci, Leonardo, 1966
    Rice Design Alliance, 1976
    Richardson, Betty, 1982
    Richardson, Sara, 1987
    Riggs, Lutah Maria, 1978
    Rinehart, Arley, 1977, 1978
    Roark, I. L., Jr., 1948
    Robertson, A. G., 1954
    Robinson, Sidney, 1973
    Roche, Kevin, 1968
    Rosa, Joseph, 1987, 1988
    Rose, Ronald, 1984
    Rosenberg, George, 1952
    Rosenstone, Robert, 1973, 1974
    Ross, Michael Franklin, 1979
    Ross, William D., 1952
    Roth, Leland, 1978
    Rouillard, Dominique, 1985
    Rucker, Karen Conan, 1985, 1986
    Ruff, Carl, 1977
    Ruocco, Ilse, 1946
    Russell, Julia, 1982
    Rydell, Roy, 1974, 1976
    Sadler, H. G., 1973
    San Diego City Council, 1984
    San Diego Museum of Art, 1979
    San Francisco State College, 1968
    Sanders, Terry, 1965
    Sanguinetti, Vittorio, 1963, 1964
    Santa Monica Landmarks Commission, 1981
    Santini, Pier Carlo, 1964
    Saturday Evening Post, 1959, 1960
    Sauer, Louis, 1968
    Sawelson-Gorse, Naomi, 1989
    Secrest, Meryle, 1988
    Serulnic, Mrs. George, 1967
    Sewell, Elaine K., 1966
    Shapira, Nathan, 1966, 1967, 1968, 1969, 1979, 1983, undated
    Shaw, Lawrence C., 1948
    Shultz, Susan, 1969
    Simo, Melanie, 1987, 1988
    Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1963
    Smith, C. Ray, 1972
    Smith, Frank Folsom, 1967
    Smith, Kathryn, 1979, 1987, 1988, undated
    Smith, Robert, 1972
    Smith, Whitney, 1970
    Smithson, Alison, 1983, 1985
    Snow, C. P., 1960, 1961
    Solomon, Barbara Probst, 1984
    Southern California Institute of Architecture, 1989
    Southwest Review, 1952
    Space Design, 1984
    Speiss, Fred, 1977, undated
    Stahlberg, Arlen, 1976
    Stanfield, Cecil E., 1949
    Stegner, Wallace, 1947, 1951
    Steinbrueck, Victor, 1964
    Stern, Robert and Lynn, 1965, 1966, 1973
    Sterner, Carl John, 1974
    Stickney, Charles, 1964, 1967
    Stone Magazine, 1965
    Strand, Janann, undated
    Straub, Calvin, 1970
    Sunset Magazine, 1981
    Sussman, Deborah, 1987, 1989, undated
    Super, Rob, 1974
    Taylor, Crombie, 1967
    Tazewell, E. Bradford, Jr., 1967
    Temko, Allan, 1957, 1966, 1970, 1988, 1989
    The Modern Quarterly, 1948
    The Pacific Spectator, 1947
    Thiry, Paul, 1949
    Tigerman, Stanley, 1965, 1977
    Toland, James, 1955, 1957
    Travers, David, 1963, 1964, 1966, 1967, 1968, 1972, 1977, 1987, undated
    Tulane University, 1982, 1983, undated
    Turner, George P., 1960
    Underhill, Anna A., 1941
    University of California, Berkeley, 1974, 1978
    University of California Extension, 1974
    University of California, Santa Barbara, 1966, 1969, 1972, 1982, 1987
    University of California, Santa Cruz, 1972, 1973, 1974, 1978, 1979
    University of Cambridge, Department of Architecture, 1975
    University of Oklahoma, 1949, 1985
    University of Pennsylvania, 1984
    University of Southern California, 1970
    University Press of Kentucky, 1974
    University Prints, 1957
    University Women's Club, 1972, 1975, 1983
    Vaccarino, Donna, 1989
    Van Doren, Phyllis, 1984
    Veret, Jean-Louis, 1960
    Ventre, Francis T., 1985
    Veronesi, Giulia, 1966, 1974
    Via, 1976
    Victor Gruen Foundation for Environmental Planning, 1972
    Victor, Michael, 1983
    Voelcker, John, 1968
    Von Breton, Harriette, 1969
    Von Eckardt, Wolf, 1981, 1983, 1984
    Vreeland, Thomas, 1965, 1969, 1974, 1984
    W. W. Norton and Co., 1966
    Walker Art Center, 1975
    Walker, Derek, 1982
    Walker, Sam, 1985
    Walton, Billy, 1986
    Ward, Robert and Sandra Williams Photography of Architecture, 1977, 1978
    Ward, Robertson, 1981
    Wasserman, Steve, 1984, 1985, 1986
    Waugh, Arthur B., 1959
    Wayne, June, 1981, 1985
    Weirick, James, 1970, 1974
    Weiss, Peggy, 1982, 1984
    Wemple, Emmet L., 1974, undated
    Western Association of Art Museums, 1967
    Wicks, Ebba L., 1949
    Wight, Frederick S., 1966
    Wilk, Christopher, 1987
    William Morris Agency, 1957
    William Morrow and Company, Inc., 1950
    Williams, Alexander Kruse, 1985
    Williams, Wayne R., 1952, 1953, 1972
    Wills, David, 1969
    Wilson, Forrest, 1972, 1975, 1983,1987
    Wilson, Richard Guy, 1981
    Winslow, Carleton Monroe, 1969, undated
    Winter, Bob, 1964, 1975, 1976, undated
    Woman's Building, 1987
    Woman's Day, 1957
    Women's Architectural League, 1981
    Wood, Donna, 1981
    Woodbridge, Sally, 1977, 1982
    Woollen, Evans, 1983, 1984
    Wright, Eric Lloyd, 1984
    Writers Guild of America, West, 1967, 1969
    Wurster, William, 1964
    Zevi, Bruno, 1959, 1960, 1963, 1965, 1974
    - General Correspondence, 1922-1929 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - General Correspondence, 1946-1952 (Box 4, Folder 39-42)